Roy Chancellor

Lifelong programmer seeking Java developer position

Life-long programmer who loves to solve problems is pursuing a career in Java software development. Passionate and tenacious about exceeding requirements to create the best possible customer experience. With a total of 25 years' experience in mechanical engineering and mathematics education, I have demonstrated mastery of finishing projects, managing multiple priorities, and communicating effectively with a wide variety of people.

Experience

2006 Mathematics Education

2006 - 2013 and 2015 - 2019

Math Master Teacher, Great Hearts Academies (2008 - 2013 / 2015 - 2019) Created mathematics curricula from Algebra 1 through Calculus 2 and delivered with passion, energy, and clarity. Mentored teachers with the goal of increasing student learning. Created the school master schedule, each year solving multiple conflicts generated by error checking code in Excel VBA.

Math Teacher, Scottsdale Unified School District (2006 - 2008)

Developed a consumer math course that taught real-life financial and business

1994 Engineering

1993 - 2006 and 2013 - 2015

skills to high school seniors

Manufacturing Engineer, Schweitzer Engineering Laboratory (2013 - 2015) Introduced new products to production by managing multiple part changes, building prototypes, and configuring ERP systems

Statistician, Intel Corporation (2005 - 2006)

Analyzed complex data sets in JMP to help development engineers make decisions about materials and solve technical problems before production **Six Sigma Master Black Belt**, Rogers Corporation (1999 - 2005)

Led a corporate-level team of black belts that completed projects across the company netting > \$1M savings over 3 years

Mechanical Engineer, Orbital Sciences Corporation (1998 - 1999)

Created a unique mechanical solution for a circuit board that cracked during shock testing and qualified the solution for flight

Process Engineer, W.L. Gore and Associates (1994 - 1998)

Designed LabView code to dial an operator's pager when a constraint machine went down and created an Access database to collect capacitance

Automated Test Programmer (Contract), EF Data (1993 - 1994)

Created a suite of test automation scripts in C that reduced time to final test satellite modems

Education

2004

1993

2019 Certificate in Java Programming, Grand Canyon University

Java programming certificate focused on core Java for developing back-end web applications. Technologies include

Graduate Certificate in Applied Statistics, Rochester Institute of Technology

M.S. Mechanical Engineering, Texas A&M University

- **Thesis**: Parameter Identification Using Nonlinear Dynamics and Chaos (article published in the ASME Journal of Vibration and Acoustics, July 1996)
- Co-created a micro controller-based active-damping system for a 1/4 car suspension by writing C code that implemented PID control
- Simulated the dynamic response of a five-pendulum test rig using C language code to solve the matrix equations of motion

1991 B.S.E. Mechanical Engineering, Arizona State University

Personal Info

Address

2014 East Anderson Drive Phoenix, Arizona 85022

Phone

480.242.6356

E-mail

roychance600@gmail.com

WWW

roychancellor.me

GitHub

github.com/roychancellor

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/roychancellor

Skills

Java: Skilled at writing object-oriented code that is clean and easy to maintain using #### technologies

C/C++: Wrote code to acquire & display data from A/D cards, communicate through RS-232, simulate dynamic

systems, and perform mathematical

computations

VBA: Wrote VBA code to automate data processes in Excel

Python: Basic skills acquired through online Udemy course

Time oderny course

HTML and CSS to create web sites.

Currently studying JavaScript and React

Data analysis: Skilled at JMP and Minitab to analyze complex data sets across a variety of disciplines

Courses

Java Programming I, II, and III

Open Source Computing

C Programming

Regression Analysis I and II

Design of Experiments I and II

Theory of Statistics I and II

Introduction to Numerical Methods